Education, School of; Records ua650
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Activities and Programs, 1927-1988; 2; 3 cubic ft.
  - Press Releases, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 25)
  - Peace Corps Training Program in India Summer, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 26)
  - Physical Education, 1970 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 27)
  - Politics and Education, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 28)
  - Program for the Improvement of College Teaching, 1965-1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 29)
  - Program for the Improvement of College Teaching, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 30)
  - Project Changeover, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 31)
  - Project Themis, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 32)
  - Reading Teachers, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 33)
  - Reading Research Center, 1973 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 34)
  - Regional Education Laboratory, 1965 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 35)
  - Regional Education Services Center, Undated (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 36)
  - Rehabilitation Counseling, 1966; Undated (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 37)
  - Research and Development Center, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 38)
  - School Psychology, 1967-1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 39)
  - Science Teachers, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 40)
  - Seminars, 1982 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 41)
  - Social Studies, 1974; Undated (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 42)
  - Special Education, 1966-1976 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 43)
  - Special Education, 1966-1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 44)
  - Special Education, 1966-1970 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Speech and Hearing Handicapped, 1975 February 1 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Spring Lecture Series on Improvement of College Teaching, 1964 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Student Teaching Center, 1966-1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Summer Conferences, 1965-1967 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Summer Institutes, 1964-1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Summer Institutes, 1964-1968 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Summer Institutes, 1964-1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Summer Institutes, 1964-1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Summer Institutes, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Summer Institutes, 1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Summer Sessions, 1963-1972 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - Surveys, 1985-1988 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Summer Workshops, 1965-6/1967 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Symposia, 1978-1982 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Task Force on Teacher Education, 1969-1972 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Teaching Centers Proposal, 1967 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - Teacher Fellowships, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Teacher Corps, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - Teacher Education, 1962-1979; Undated (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Teacher Education, 1962-1979; Undated (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Teaching of English as a Second Language, 1971-1985 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Traffic Safety Education, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Training of Teachers of Teachers (T-T-T), 1968-1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)
  - Training Program for Subject Supervisors, 1969-1972 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 25)
  - Two Year College Consortium, 1967-1970 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 26)
  - The University-Community Cooperative Centers For Individual Development, Undated (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 27)
  - United States Dependent Schools in Europe, 1972 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 28)
  - Urban Education, Syracuse University, 1966-1968 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 29)
  - Use of Undergraduates in Teaching, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 30)
  - Vocational Rehabilitation, 1966-1969 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 31)
  - Wisconsin Teacher Competence Project, 1964 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 32)
  - Workshops, 1965-1976 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 33)
  - Workshops, 1965-1976 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 34)
  - Workshops, 1979 (Box 3 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 35)
- Publications, 1953-1988; 3; 2.66 cubic ft.
  This series includes newsletters, reports, studies, proposals and proceedings of conferences published by the School of Education. The reports and studies comprise those officially published by the School of Education either by itself or in conjunction with other bodies. The proposals include the Bilingual Education Program, the In-Service Collegiate Summer Institute, training and research for state departments of education. Newsletters include Forerunner which contained a calendar of events sponsored by the School of Education. This series also includes general publications of the School of Education such as annual reports, accreditation reports, directories of faculty and staff by year, telephone directories of the School of Education by year, handbooks for student teaching and for student teachers, and three-year academic plans. The proceedings of conferences include the New York State Education Forum of 1984 and the 1983 conference on electronic learning. Student papers in Box 1 and Box 2 are restricted. Consult a staff member for details.
  Most of the materials in this series are memoranda that represent communications between committee members as well as between committee members and university administration. There are also meeting minutes, reports, correspondence and class materials. For an overview of the program's creation, see Box 2, Folder 8, "Report on School of Education", which is composed of materials organized by Paul Bulger and Lou Ismay.
  - Annual Report, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 3-4)
  - Annual Report, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 6-7)
  - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 8-9)
  - Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 10-11)
  - Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 12-13)
  - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 14-15)
  - Bilingual Bicultural Education Fellowship Program, 1977 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Student Paper, "A Study of the Select Seminar on Teacher Evaluation II", for EPDE 757, 1986 May 13 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Casdagram, 1968-1979 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Certification Registration Report, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Curtis, Thorns, The Middle School, 1967 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Student Paper, "The Problem of Drop Outs from Our School System", Ed. 251, 1955 January (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Diary of Student Teaching, 1953 September 14-1953 November 6 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Directory, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Directory, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Directory, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Directory, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Directory, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 27)
  - Directory of Education, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 28)
  - Directory, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 29)
  - Directory, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 30)
  - Directory, School of Education Faculty, Undated (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 31-32)
  - Directory, School of Education Faculty, 1983 Fall (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 33)
  - Directory, School of Education Faculty, 1984 Fall (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 34)
  - Directory, School of Education Faculty, 1985 Fall (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 35)
  - Directory, School of Education Faculty, 1986 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 36)
  - Directory, School of Education Faculty, 1987 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 37)
  - Directory, Telephone, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 38)
  - Directory, Telephone, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 39)
  - Directory, Telephone, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 40)
  - Directory, Telephone, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 41)
  - Directory, Telephone, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 42)
  - Doctoral Dissertations, 1963-1985 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 43)
  - Drugs: A Study Guide by James P. Kielt, 1976 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 44)
  - Educational Computer Consortiums of the Capital Area Newsletter, Vol. 1-2, 1986 (Box 1 (3-Publications), Folder 45)
  - Educational Programs For the Culturally Deprived, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Educational Television At SUNYA, 1963 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 2)
  - An Experimental Program For Training Child Guidance Specialists in Puerto-Rico, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Fairbanks, R.E, "A Follow-up of New York State Bookkeeping Students", 1967 September (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Final Narrative Report, Institute In Self Paced Instructional Strategies, 1973 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Forerunner, 1981 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Fowler, Charles. W; Paul F. Hooker, M. Lee Upcraft, "Interests of Junior High School Students", 1961 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Free and Inexpensive Materials for Teaching About the Negro in America, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Gerbino, Kathryn A., and David W. Chapmon, "Capital District Residents View Their Public Schools: A Public Opinion Survey", 1984 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 9)
  - A Handbook for Off-campus Student Teaching, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 10)
  - A Handbook for Student Teachers, 1988 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 11)
  - A Handbook for Student Teaching Center Cooperating Teachers, 1988 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Inside Education, 1972 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Institute in Science Teaching Report, 1966 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Institute in Self-Paced Instructional Strategies: Final Narrative Report, 1973 July 2-1973 July 20 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Institute for In-service Education of Administrative Leaders of Higher Education, 1969-1972 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Institute in Self-Paced Instructional Strategies: Interim Narrative Report, 1974 July 1-1974 July 19 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 17-18)
  - Institutional Report to NCATE, Vol. 1, 1970 January (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Institutional Report to NCATE, Vol. 2, 1970 January (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Institutional Report to NCATE, Vol. 3, 1970 January (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 21-25)
  - Institutional Report to NCATE, Vol. 4, 1970 January (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Institutional Report to NCATE, Vol. 5, 1970 January (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 27)
  - Intermediate and Final Narrative Report, Institute for the Development of Occupational Competences, 1977 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 28)
  - Interim Narrative Report Institute for Coping with Change in Business Education at Urban Schools, 1978 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 29)
  - James, Charles, the Negro Writer in America, Undated (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 30)
  - Light, Richard L., and Pat Furey, "Aspects of Culture in the TESL Classroom", 1975 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 31)
  - Media Guide to Resources, 1984 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 32)
  - McPherson, Michael S., "Federal Student Aid Policy: Can We Learn from Experience?", 1985 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 33)
  - Student Project, "Project Number One: Collection of Newspaper Articles Concerning the Loss and Gain of Employment with the Labor Market", Ed. 605, 1967 October (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 34)
  - "The Negro in the Last 100 Years", Social Studies Resource Unit, Undated (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 35)
  - Newsletter, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 36)
  - New York State Committee of English Educators of the New York State English Council Bulletin, No. 2 July 1969, No.3, 1970 August (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 37)
  - New York State Education Forum 1984 Conference Proceedings (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 38)
  - O'Brien, C.J., and D.W. Chapman, Capital District Residents Rate Their Public Schools: Second Annual Opinion Survey, 1985 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 39)
  - Off-Campus Student Teaching: A Handbook, 1960 (Box 2 (3-Publications), Folder 40)
  - A Pilot Study in Media Feasibility in Selected College Courses, 1969 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Proceedings of Conference on Electronic Learning, 1983 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Proposal, Bilingual Education Project, 1974 May 8 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Proposal, Bilingual Education Program, 1976 May 21 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Proposal, Inservice Collegiate Summer Institute, 1974 January 28 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Proposal for Training and Research Institute for State Departments of Education, 1965 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Report of Committee on Off-Campus Student Teaching, Undated (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Report to National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1961 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Smith, C. Currien, "New Wine in Old Bottles: or the Introduction of the Merit Concept into the Teachers College Salary Program", 1955 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 9)
  - A Student's Guide to the SUNYA Campus, 1974 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Student Handbook, 1988 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Teacher Training Institute: Adult Basic Education, 1967 July 23-1967 August 11 (Box 3 (3-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Teacher-Training Institute: Adult Basic Education, 1967 July 23-1967 August 11 (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 1-2)
  - Teacher-Training Institute: Adult Basic Education, 1969 July 20-1969 August 8 (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 3-4)
  - Teaching Languages in College, 1985 (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Three Year Academic Plan, 1977 January (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 6-7)
  - Three Year Academic Plan, ca. 1979 (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Three Year Academic Plan, 1981 (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Webb, Eugene, "The Attitudes of a Sample of the Class of 1954 on the Education Department of New York State College for Teachers, Albany", Undated (Box 4 (3-Publications), Folder 10)
- Web Archives, 1997 June 7-2016 September 17; 4; 858 captures
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.
  Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu, library.albany.edu, events.albany.edu, cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Web Archives
  - http://www.albany.edu/education/ - University Archives collection, 2013 May 8-2016 September 17 (Web-archive 1)
  - WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/education/, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details), 2013 May 8-2016 September 17 (Warc 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in researching with web archives.
  - http://www.albany.edu/education/ - Internet Archive collection, 1997 June 7-2016 September 17 (Web-archive 2)